<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <docs>https://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
    <title>Sam Bateman&#39;s Personal Website</title>
    <link>https://bateman.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Sam Bateman&#39;s Personal Website</description>
    <ttl>1440</ttl>
    <generator>Hugo 0.68.3</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 22:06:56 UT</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://bateman.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://bateman.io/project/</link>
      <dc:creator>Sam Bateman</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://bateman.io/project/</guid>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://bateman.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 07:26:08 UT</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Sam Bateman</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://bateman.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, my name is Sam Bateman, and right now, I do robotics and mapping.
I am a recent grad from the University of Colorado - Boulder, where I graduated with a B.S. in Computer Science and a B.S. in Applied Mathematics. I did my senior thesis work in the Autonomous Robotics and Perception Group in the Department of Computer Science, focusing on developing algorithms to enable a dynamic, semantic, Simultaneous Localization and Mapping (SLAM).</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[Hi, my name is Sam Bateman, and right now, I do robotics and mapping.
I am a recent grad from the University of Colorado - Boulder, where I graduated with a B.S. in Computer Science and a B.S. in Applied Mathematics. I did my senior thesis work in the Autonomous Robotics and Perception Group in the Department of Computer Science, focusing on developing algorithms to enable a dynamic, semantic, Simultaneous Localization and Mapping (SLAM). I also worked in the Autonomous Vehicle Systems Laboratory in the Department of Aerospace Engineering primarily on the visualization for Basilisk, which is a high fidelity, high performance astrodynamics simulation framework in Python, while assisting in various research projects. I also had a couple internships, including a summer research internship at MIT Lincoln Labs.
Today, I am lucky to work as a Software Engineer on the Autonomy - Localization and Mapping team at a autonomous local delivery startup in the Bay Area called Nuro with a number of brilliant engineers and researchers.
 My primary research interests are in localization, mapping, perception, and machine learning. More specifically, I am interested in collaborative perception, sensor fusion, long-term autonomy, and bringing together geometric and learned methods to improve the state of the art. I also am known to be easily drawn into any interesting problem which can use a level of mathematical inclination. Feel free to check out my previous projects to get a sampling.
 In my free time, I like reading, playing video games (specifically League of Legends and Counter Strike: Global Offensive right now) and spending time with my friends.
Feel free to contact me at sam@bateman.io if you have any questions or inquiries.
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://bateman.io/post/</link>
      <dc:creator>Sam Bateman</dc:creator>
      <guid>https://bateman.io/post/</guid>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
